/* Created and coded by Abhilash Narayan */
/* Quiz source: w3schools.com */
var quiz = {
    "JS": [
    {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "What is USP full form?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Unlimited selling point",
    "b": "Unique showcase point.",
    "c": "Unique selling Point",
    "d": "Unique selling porpotional"
    
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Unique selling point",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "USP can be define in one sentence",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "It is a worst part of a business",
    "b": "It is important for marketing",
    "c": "It is only use for single business",
    "d": "it is use for internet advertisment only"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "It is important for marketing",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "Extraction of USP _______________",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "analyze the need of targated audience",
    "b": "analyze market need",
    "c": "analyze work load",
    "d": "divide work in a huge team",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "analyze the need of targated audience",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "know your skills is the key point of Unique selling point?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "True",
    "b": "False"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "True",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "A logo is ___________ of the Brand",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Need",
    "b": "backbone",
    "c": "structure",
    "d": "identity",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "identity",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "A customer desire is ______________.",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "That's necessary of the product",
    "b": "Related to the product",
    "c": "What he wish to be in product but not necessary",
    "d": "Both A & B"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Both A & B",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "Choose incorrect option, Guidlines are necessary because______________",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "It is an easy guide to refer to when handing over the project",
    "b": "When something awful happens, you can reffer them to the guidlines",
    "c": "Contains documentation of product in a business",
    "d": "Helps to make the design more solid"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "When something awful happens, you can reffer them to the guidlines",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "Choose incorrect option, A design layout should",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Properly printed",
    "b": "Represent USP",
    "c": "Meet customer needs",
    "d": " Balance"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Properly printed",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "Choose incorrect option, Adobe photoshop & Corel draw are use for same purpose working.",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "True",
    "b": "False"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "False",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "How many bars we can see in the Corel draw Interface at the start?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "5",
    "b": "2",
    "c": "4",
    "d": "6",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "5",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "Corel Draw is a Raster base software and works on pixels.",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "True",
    "b": "False"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "False",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "Branding Guidlines means",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "client name, age, education",
    "b": "size, color, theme",
    "c": "unique idea",
    "d": "Focus on USPs"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "size, color, theme",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "How to Create Target Personas with The Right Demographics",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "height, fair complexion, long hair",
    "b": "age, gender, location",
    "c": "identify by car or bike"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "age, gender, location",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "Why Unique selling point is important?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "customer need",
    "b": "strategy for attracting new customers",
    "c": "market need "
    }
    ],
    "answer": "strategy for attracting new customers",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "Corel Draw is a :",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Raster Software",
    "b": "Tracing Software",
    "c": "Bitmap Software",
    "d": "Vector Software"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Vector Software",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "How many bars we can find in Corel Draw Interface",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "4",
    "b": "3",
    "c": "5",
    "d": "6"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "5",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "In corel Draw, shortcut key of pick tool is :",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "ctrl + spacebar",
    "b": "ctrl + V",
    "c": "V",
    "d": "A"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "ctrl + spacebar",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "In corel Draw, shortcut key of Shape tool is :",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "F10",
    "b": "F6",
    "c": "F8",
    "d": "F9"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "F10",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "Virtual Segment Delete Tool Use for :",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "cut unwanted part from an image",
    "b": "divide object in 2 parts",
    "c": "divide object in Multiple parts",
    "d": "cut unwanted lines from an object"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "cut unwanted lines from an object",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "What fill tool would a person use if she/he wanted to fill an object with hearts?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Uniform",
    "b": "Transparent",
    "c": "Fountain",
    "d": "Pattern",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Uniform",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    }
    ]
    }
    var quizApp = function () {
    this.score = 0;
    this.qno = 1;
    this.currentque = 0;
    var totalque = quiz.JS.length;
    this.displayQuiz = function (cque) {
    this.currentque = cque;
    if (this.currentque < totalque) {
    $("#tque").html(totalque);
    $("#previous").attr("disabled", false);
    $("#next").attr("disabled", false);
    $("#qid").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].id + '.');
    $("#question").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].question);
    $("#question-options").html("");
    for (var key in quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0]) {
    if (quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0].hasOwnProperty(key)) {
    $("#question-options").append(
    "<div class='form-check option-block'>" +
    "<label class='form-check-label'>" +
    "<input type='radio' class='form-check-input' name='option' id='q" + key + "' value='" + quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] + "'><span id='optionval'>" +
    quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] +
    "</span></label>"
    );
    }
    }
    }
    if (this.currentque <= 0) {
    $("#previous").attr("disabled", true);
    }
    if (this.currentque >= totalque) {
    $('#next').attr('disabled', true);
    for (var i = 0; i < totalque; i++) {
    this.score = this.score + quiz.JS[i].score;
    }
    return this.showResult(this.score);
    }
    }
    this.showResult = function (scr) {
    $("#result").addClass('result');
    $("#result").html("<h1 class='res-header'>Total Score: &nbsp;" + scr + '/' + totalque + "</h1>");
    for (var j = 0; j < totalque; j++) {
    var res;
    if (quiz.JS[j].score == 0) {
    res = '<span class="wrong">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-remove c-wrong"></i>';
    } else {
    res = '<span class="correct">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-check c-correct"></i>';
    }
    $("#result").append(
    '<div class="result-question"><span>Q ' + quiz.JS[j].id + '</span> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].question + '</div>' +
    '<div><b>Correct answer:</b> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].answer + '</div>' +
    '<div class="last-row"><b>Score:</b> &nbsp;' + res +
    '</div>'
    );
    }
    }
    this.checkAnswer = function (option) {
    var answer = quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer;
    option = option.replace(/</g, "&lt;") //for <
    option = option.replace(/>/g, "&gt;") //for >
    option = option.replace(/"/g, "&quot;")
    if (option == quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer) {
    if (quiz.JS[this.currentque].score == "") {
    quiz.JS[this.currentque].score = 1;
    quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "correct";
    }
    } else {
    quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "wrong";
    }
    }
    this.changeQuestion = function (cque) {
    this.currentque = this.currentque + cque;
    this.displayQuiz(this.currentque);
    }
    }
    var jsq = new quizApp();
    var selectedopt;
    $(document).ready(function () {
    jsq.displayQuiz(0);
    $('#question-options').on('change', 'input[type=radio][name=option]', function (e) {
    //var radio = $(this).find('input:radio');
    $(this).prop("checked", true);
    selectedopt = $(this).val();
    });
    });
    $('#next').click(function (e) {
    e.preventDefault();
    if (selectedopt) {
    jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
    }
    jsq.changeQuestion(1);
    });
    $('#previous').click(function (e) {
    e.preventDefault();
    if (selectedopt) {
    jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
    }
    jsq.changeQuestion(-1);
    });